Gregg Smith Papers
Gregg Smith Papers
- Compositions
  - Large symphonic works, Christmas and folk
    - Old Folks Quadrille [title in donor inventory is "Stephen Foster Quadriled Orchestrations"]
      - Choral score, copies, 8 ½ x 11 (Oversize 23)
      - Unison melodies and string quartet realizations by Foster, copies (Oversize 23)
    - Prayer for Peace
      - Full score, copied and marked (Oversize 23)
      - Parts, copied and marked (Oversize 23)
      - Piano vocal score, vellums and vellum copies (Oversize 23)
    - Missa Brevis (Mass for St. Peter's)
      - Piano vocal score, vellums (Oversize 23)
    - Suite of Antiphonal Carols
      - Full score, vellums (Oversize 23)
      - Full score, copies (Oversize 23)
      - Compositional sketches (Oversize 23)
    - We wish you a merry Christmas
      - Choral manuscripts, copies (Oversize 23)
  - Operas
    This series contains original operas and musicals by Smith. For Smith's arrangements of popular works from operas by others, see Popular song arrangements and compositions below.
    - Adirondack Journal [alternate title: Adirondack folk musical]
      - Full score, computer printout with notes and libretto text intermingled, in red binder (Box 4)
      - Folk Opera Full Scores [Adirondack Journal, full score], smith_gre_001; From donor inventory: "two floppy disks containing computer manuscript files"; Floppy disk: 3 ½ inch (Box 18)
      - Folk Opera Parts [Adirondack Journal, parts], smith_gre_002; From donor inventory: "two floppy disks containing computer manuscript files"; Floppy disk: 3 ½ inch (Box 18)
      - Parts, violin, 2 songs only: A'lumberin' I will go and The Romany sign (Box 5)
      - Sketches (Box 5)
    - Bartleby [music by Gregg Smith, Libretto by Kim Rich]
      - Librettos, bound (Box 5)
      - Sketches, handwritten (Oversize 25)
    - Chicken Little
      - Choral parts, version 1 (6-part), vellums (Oversize 24)
      - Choral parts, version 2 (5-part), vellums (Oversize 24)
      - Parts, handwritten (Oversize 24)
      - Piano score, copies, includes extra pages (37-38) from different set (Oversize 42)
      - Piano score, copy (Oversize 24)
      - Piano vocal score, handwritten copies (Oversize 24)
      - Piano vocal score, copied, bound and marked, 2 copies, 1 with hand-illustrated cover (Oversize 24)
      - Sketches, handwritten (Oversize 24)
    - Dreameater
      - Libretto and scene synopsis (Box 5)
      - Piano vocal score, "Ordinary Girl", handwritten plus copy of page 1 (Oversize 24)
      - Piano vocal score, computer printout with revisions (Box 5)
      - Sketches, handwritten, and miscellaneous pages, computer printout (Box 5)
    - The Other Wise Man
      - Full orchestral score, handwritten, bound (Oversize 42)
      - Piano vocal score, vellums (Box 5)
      - Piano vocal score, copy, bound (Oversize 42)
    - Pretty Good Company ["cabaret song cycle based on the epigrams of Gomer Rees"]
      - Full score, mix of handwritten and copies, in 3-ring binder (Oversize 25)
      - Piano vocal score, vellums (incomplete) (Oversize 25)
      - Piano vocal score, copies, with revisions (incomplete) (Oversize 25)
      - Libretto (Box 5)
      - Salted Peanuts pages (Oversize 25)
        It was unclear where these pages belonged, so they have been foldered separately.
      - Sketches (Oversize 25)
      - Random pages (Oversize 25)
    - Rip Van Winkle
      - Full orchestral score, handwritten (Oversize 24)
      - Full orchestral score, handwritten copy (not same as above), partial (Box 5)
      - Choral parts, children's choir, vellums (Box 5)
      - Choral parts, men's, women's, and narrator (partial) (Box 5)
      - Parts, handwritten (Oversize 24)
      - Parts, vellums (Oversize 24)
      - Parts, miscellaneous copies (Box 5)
      - Piano vocal score copies, marked, unmarked, partial, possibly several copies mixed together; original order has been preserved (Box 5)
      - Miscellaneous text items, libretto, synopsis of characters and scenes, story copied from unidentified book, rehearsal schedule (Box 5)
    - The Storyteller
      - Full score, computer printout in two binders [binder 1, flowered cover], missing "Pig in Flowers"; contains multiple copies of many of the songs, plus an extra copy of "Mischief" which is in binder 2 (Box 4)
      - Full score, computer printout in two binders [binder 2, labeled] (Box 4)
      - Children's choir parts, computer printout (Box 6)
      - Libretto draft, with notes (Box 6)
      - Libretto, bound and marked (Box 6)
      - Parts, mix of computer printout and copies, some marked, 3 folders (Box 6)
      - Piano vocal score, computer printout, marked, in blue binder (Box 4)
      - Piano vocal score, bound for publication (Box 6)
      - The Storyteller Practice, smith_gre_003; practice tape for Smith's original opera The Storyteller; 1/8 inch audio cassette; running time 60:00 (Box 18)
      - Song list (Box 6)
      - String transcription by Robert Ross, computer printout, marked (Box 6)
      - Sketches, handwritten (Oversize 24)
  - Orchestral/choral works, miscellaneous
    - Adirondack Symphony, donor inventory states, "[W]e hypothesize that this is an early orchestrated version of what would later become A Child's Garden of Verses"
      - Full score, 3d movement, handwritten (Oversize 10)
      - Full score, 3d movement, copied and bound (Box 7)
      - Piano vocal score, incomplete (Box 7)
    - Alleluia vom Himmel Hoch
      - Parts, handwritten (Oversize 26)
      - Piano vocal, vellums (Oversize 26)
    - Brass Quintet
      - Full score, handwritten (incomplete) and handwritten sketches (Oversize 26)
      - Full score, computer printout (Oversize 26)
    - Chief Seattle
      - Full score, 8-1/2 x 11 copy (Box 7)
      - Full score, copies (incomplete) (Box 7)
      - Libretto and text of original speech (Box 7)
    - A Child's Garden of Verses
      - Fragments, mix of computer printout, handwritten, handwritten copies (Box 7)
    - Eleven Palindromes
      - Full score, handwritten copy (Oversize 26)
      - Clarinet part, computer printout (Oversize 26)
    - Epigrams [Gomer Rees]
      - Solo version, vellums (Oversize 26)
      - Gomer's texts (Oversize 26)
    - Gloria for 2 choirs and brass quintet
      - Full score, vellums (Oversize 26)
      - Full score, copied and marked (Oversize 26)
      - Parts, vellums (Oversize 26)
      - Parts, computer printout, marked (Oversize 26)
      - Piano vocal score, copy, marked; does not seem to match, possibly from different Gloria? (Oversize 26)
    - Grand Palindrome
      - Full orchestral score (conductor), handwritten and marked (Oversize 27)
      - Parts, handwritten (Oversize 27)
      - Parts, copied (Oversize 27)
    - A Mary Trilogy [3 parts: Ave Maria, Regina Coeli, Salve Regina]
      - Full score, handwritten, pp 1-2 of Regina Coeli (Oversize 27)
      - Full score and parts, vellums (Oversize 27)
      - Full score, copies, Regina Coeli and Salve Regina (Oversize 27)
      - Parts, copied (Oversize 27)
    - Mass in Space
      - Full score, vellums (Oversize 27)
      - Full score, computer printout, noted as "FINAL" (Box 7)
      - Full score, copy, heavily annotated (Box 7)
      - Full score, partial copies and computer printouts (Box 7)
      - Sketches, computer printout (Box 7)
    - Offertorium on Psalm 24
      - Full score, vellums (Oversize 27)
      - Full score, copy, bound (Oversize 27)
    - Recordare (Kurt Weill)
      - Full score, handwritten (Oversize 28)
      - Parts, handwritten (Oversize 28)
    - Scherzo and Blues
      - Full score, vellums (Oversize 28)
      - Full score, copies (multiple, some with marks, some incomplete, not in good order) (Oversize 28)
      - Parts, vellums and a few copied pages (Oversize 28)
      - Parts, copied (Oversize 28)
      - Piano vocal score, bound, a few markings (Oversize 28)
    - Songs from a Liberal Heart
      - Full score, computer printout (Box 7)
      - Parts, computer printout (Box 7)
      - Piano vocal, computer printout (Box 7)
    - Miscellaneous choral arrangements
      - Ahay tuburan, handwritten copy, marked (Box 7)
      - The Cuckoo, choral manuscript and solo manuscript (Box 7)
      - Doo wop madrigals, handwritten Cool April, My Heart, Il est bon; copies of those and other fragments (Oversize 28)
      - Evening for two choruses, full score, vellums (Oversize 28)
      - Evening for two choruses, full score, copies and computer printout (Oversize 28)
      - Exultate Deo, full score, vellums (Box 7)
      - Exultate Deo, full score, copies (Box 7)
      - Halley's Comet, vellums (Box 7)
      - Holiday Harmonies, full score, handwritten copy (Oversize 28)
      - If music be the food of love, "For LISCA's 20th"; full score and treble melody, vellums (Oversize 28)
      - Jamaican songs, computer printouts (Box 7)
      - Jerusalem, full score, several; mix of handwritten, vellums and vellum copies, many with markings (Oversize 28)
      - Patapan, manuscript copy, handwritten carbon (Oversize 28)
      - Riqui, Riqui, Riqurran, partial manuscript (Box 7)
      - Set me as a seal, "for Fred and Joyce Wilkins", partial manuscript copy (Box 7)
      - Shakespeare madrigals, manuscript copies (Box 7)
      - A Simple mass, vellums (Box 7)
      - Suogon, Welsh carol; manuscript copy (Box 8)
    - Miscellaneous classical orchestrations/arrangements
      - L'Amour de moi [Tiersot], parts, handwritten (Oversize 29)
      - L'Amour de moi [Tiersot], parts, copied (Oversize 29)
      - Battle of Stonington [Brandon], parts, text and fragments, all copies (Oversize 29)
      - Circus Band [Ives], full score and parts, handwritten (Oversize 29)
      - Circus Band [Ives], full score and parts, copied (Oversize 29)
      - Jesu joy of man's desiring [Bach], parts, handwritten (Oversize 29)
      - Jesu joy of man's desiring [Bach], parts, copies, incomplete (Oversize 29)
      - Pavane (op. 30) [Faure], full score and parts, handwritten (parts incomplete) (Oversize 29)
      - Pavane (op. 30) [Faure], full score and parts, copies (Oversize 29)
      - Pavane (op. 30) [Faure], 1952 published edition with hand-written revisions to text (Oversize 29)
      - Revecy venir [le Jeune], full score, handwritten; possibly connected with Doo Wop Madrigals, which includes title "Revecy" (Oversize 29)
      - Revecy venir [le Jeune], full score, copies; possibly connected with Doo Wop Madrigals, which includes title "Revecy" (Oversize 29)
      - Three Latin madrigals (published as "Latin Madrigals"), vellums and vellum copies (Box 8)
    - Miscellaneous sketches, most are handwritten and unidentified; includes fragment "Irish blessing for Roz"; 2 folders (Oversize 29)
  - Popular song arrangements and compositions
    - Autumn Leaves (Nat King Cole)
      - Parts, vellum (Oversize 30)
      - Parts, copied (Oversize 30)
    - Babes in Toyland (Victor Herbert)
      - Full score, Toyland, handwritten (Oversize 30)
      - Parts, Toyland, handwritten (Oversize 30)
      - Parts, selected songs, handwritten, Jane, Never mind Bo-Peep, Our castle in Spain (Oversize 30)
      - Piano vocal score, Toyland, with notes (Oversize 30)
    - Beautiful Dreamer (Stephen Foster)
      - Full score, handwritten (Oversize 30)
      - Piano vocal score (copy of published Foster version), with arrangement marks and notes (Oversize 30)
    - By Strauss (Gershwin)
      - Full score, conductor's copy, handwritten copy (Oversize 41)
      - Choral score, a capella, handwritten copy (Oversize 30)
      - Parts, copied (1 pg handwritten) (Oversize 30)
    - Dearly Beloved (Johnny Mercer)
      - Choral score, vellums (Oversize 30)
      - Choral score copy and choral score reduction, copies (Oversize 30)
      - Parts, handwritten (incomplete) (Oversize 30)
    - It's a Grand Night for Singing (Rodgers and Hammerstein)
      - Full score, handwritten (Oversize 41)
      - Full score, copied and marked (Oversize 41)
      - Full score, conductor's copy, computer printout (Oversize 30)
      - Parts, computer printout (Oversize 30)
    - Let 'em Eat Cake (George Gershwin), appears to be incomplete; foldered in 3 sets based on size, order, and paper vs vellums
      - Full score, copies [set A], 3 folders (Oversize 31)
      - Full score, copies [set B] (Oversize 31)
      - Full score, vellums [set C] (Oversize 31)
    - Lonely Boy (Andrew Gold?)
      - Full orchestral score, handwritten and marked (Oversize 41)
      - Full orchestral score, copied and bound (Oversize 41)
      - Piano vocal score, copy, and typed libretto (Oversize 41)
    - Mlle. Modiste (Victor Herbert)
      - Full orchestral score, copied and bound (Oversize 32)
      - Parts, handwritten, 2 folders (Oversize 32)
    - Most Gentlemen
      - Full score, handwritten (Oversize 41)
      - Full orchestral score, handwritten copy (Oversize 41)
      - Parts, handwritten (Oversize 32)
      - Piano vocal score, copy, with markings; 1 page sketch, handwritten; text, copy, with markings (Oversize 32)
    - Naughty Marietta (Victor Herbert)
      - Parts, handwritten, 2 folders (Oversize 33)
      - Piano part [?], Tramp Tramp, 1 pg vellum and copy (Oversize 33)
    - New Yorkers Never Grow Up (Gregg Smith, based on epigram by Gomer Reese)
      - Full score, conductor's, computer printout (Oversize 33)
      - Parts, computer printout (Oversize 33)
      - Piano vocal score, computer printout (Oversize 33)
    - Porgy and Bess (George Gershwin)
      - Full score, Robbins' death scene, handwritten (Oversize 41)
      - Piano vocal score, Robbins' death scene, with notes; piano vocal score, "Porgy and Bess Selection" (Oversize 33)
    - Red Mill (Victor Herbert)
      - Full orchestral score, copied and bound (Oversize 33)
    - Send in the Clowns (Stephen Sondheim)
      - Full orchestral score, handwritten and handwritten copy (Oversize 41)
      - Parts, handwritten (Oversize 34)
      - Piano vocal score, photocopy of published Sondheim version (Oversize 34)
    - Suspension *** Suspicion? Elvis? ***
      - Full score, copied and marked; full score, reduced copy (Oversize 34)
      - Parts, handwritten (Oversize 34)
      - Piano vocal (?) score, vellums (Oversize 34)
    - Sweetheart
      - Full orchestral score, copied and bound (Oversize 34)
    - Three Sondheim Songs, chamber arrangements
      - Choral arrangement, "I remember", handwritten copies (Oversize 34)
      - Parts, all three songs, handwritten, piano, trumpet, clarinet, violin, viola, cello (Oversize 34)
    - Waltz [Sondheim]
      - Full score, handwritten (Oversize 41)
    - Miscellaneous arrangements
      - Copies and computer printouts, some with notes (Oversize 34)
        Canzonet
        Deep purple
        Great day
        I watch the love parade
        Let's call the whole thing off
        Love walked in
        Mood indigo
        Poor Pierrot
        Taking a chance on love
      - Vellums (Oversize 34)
        Birth of the blues
        Bloom
        Blue Monday
        College medley
        Freshman years
        Moonlight in Vermont
        New moon
        On the street where you live
        Where love dwells
        Unidentified, 2 pages
      - Full scores, handwritten (Oversize 41)
        Berlin medley
        Canzonet, "The night was made for love"
        I dream too much
        It don't mean a thing
        Jolly tar
        Leonora
        Mandarin
        Overture 23
        Sing of Spring
        Swanee River, 1 pg
  - Unpublished choral manuscripts
    - 9/11/2001, mix of handwritten, computer printouts, some marked; includes two pieces titled "In memoriam" (Oversize 35)
    - Adama, Israeli folk song; 1 manuscript, handwritten score with revision (Oversize 35)
    - Alleluia, brass parts and original sheets (Oversize 35)
    - Adirondack children's songs, computer printout, bound (Box 8)
      See also Correspondence: Tagg, Barbara and Memorabilia > Adirondack Children's Chorus.
    - Amazing grace, for mezzo-soprano and organ (Box 8)
    - L'Ane et le loup, handwritten and copied manuscripts, translations, revisions, etc. (Oversize 35)
    - Ascension Song, "for Tom Schmidt in memory of his mother" (Box 8)
    - Au Claire de la lune, bells and boys' choir (Box 8)
    - Ave Maria, includes vellums; 2 folders (Oversize 35)
    - B'rohos Shel Hanukah, 2 copies, 1 marked (Box 8)
    - Babe of Bethlehem, mix of handwritten and copies; includes parts, press, and research notes (Oversize 35)
    - Benedictus, piano-vocal, computer printout (Box 8)
    - Black is the color, handwritten copied, computer printout (Box 8)
    - Calamus Songs, handwritten copied and bound (Box 8)
    - Canons, miscellaneous, mix of handwritten and vellums; includes "A catch" and "An immorality" (Oversize 35)
    - Cantata for Holy Week, includes full score, choral score, choral score vellum, full score vellum, oboe part, and compositional sketches; 2 folders (Oversize 35)
    - Captain Kidd, 1 pg., handwritten; oboe part, handwritten (Oversize 35)
    - Carol's Canon, for Carol Weitzenkamp, see also Correspondence: Weitzenkamp Carol, 11/4/2000 (Box 8)
    - Chorale, for Fred Thayer and Lycoming College Concert Choir; computer printouts, some marked (Box 8)
    - A Christmas story, computer printout, marked (Box 8)
    - Christmas cantata, handwritten (Oversize 35)
    - Clarinet sonata, vellums and vellum copies (Oversize 35)
    - Clarinet sonata, computer printouts; 2 folders (Box 8)
    - Coro di trittico, based on hymn, "O God our help in ages past"; handwritten copy (Box 8)
    - Deep Peace, text, handwritten sketch, computerized and further revised sketch, 1st and final draft (Oversize 35)
    - Double sonata, full score and texts/program materials; 2 folders (Box 8)
    - Duo for two clarinets, handwritten copy (Box 8)
    - Early choruses, 3 songs of beauty; Hosanna; For Ann Gregory; Love the wild swan; Essay on freedom; With rue my heart is laden; At the last; The Robin; Can honey distil such fragrance; unidentified, possible related to 'High flight' or 'Essay on freedom' (Oversize 36)
    - Einstein quotations, vellums (Oversize 36)
    - Election of 1968, title on folder says "Election '72"; vellums (Box 8)
    - Eleemosynary Spirit, commemorating the 60th year of the Henry Luce Foundation; computer printouts (Box 8)
    - Elegy for Jacques, manuscript copy (Oversize 36)
    - Es ist ein schnee gefallen, manuscript copy (Oversize 36)
    - Ev'ry time, manuscript copy (Box 8)
    - Fanfare for 2 clarinets, choral manuscript, manuscript copy (Box 8)
    - Fallen angels, "cycle of ten songs and an interlude for soprano, clarinet and piano"; full score, computer printout, marked; list of songs (Box 8)
    - Fallen Angels - Gregg Smith / Takolas Trio, smith_gre_004; 1/8 inch audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Box 18)
    - Fantasy sonata for viola, "written for Jerry Kesmala[?]"; handwritten (Oversize 36)
    - The First dandelion, vellums and vellum copy (Oversize 36)
    - Five Sandburg songs, full score, vellums (Box 8)
    - Five Sandburg songs, full score, copy (Box 8)
    - Five Sandburg songs, text, copied from "Complete Poems" (Box 8)
    - Four canzonets, full score, copied, with added CI part handwritten (Oversize 36)
    - Four canzonets, vocal score, vellums (Oversize 36)
    - Four canzonets, vocal score, multiple copies (Oversize 36)
    - Four irradiations, vellums (Oversize 36)
    - [Frank and Barbara Christmas piece], handwritten copies (Box 8)
    - Friends, computer printout (Box 8)
    - Fugetto for solo sax, handwritten (Oversize 36)
    - Give me Jesus, includes copy of original hymn (Box 9)
    - Green grows the holly and Merry Christmas, handwritten copied and marked (Oversize 36)
    - Hail to the hills of Westwood, mimeographed copies (Box 9)
    - Holy, 1992; "for Paul Hill and the Paul Hill Chorale 25th anniversary" (Box 9)
    - How can you lie so still, full score, mix of handwritten and copies (Oversize 36)
    - Hymn of the day, vocal and bell score, copies (Box 9)
    - I hear America singing, computer printout, letter from publisher requesting corrections/additions (Box 9)
    - I ride old Paint, manuscript copies (Oversize 36)
    - I was glad, copy of marked computer printout (Box 9)
    - I will sing to the Lord, voice and organ; computer printouts (Box 9)
    - Joseph lieber, Joseph meine, full score, parts; mix of handwritten copies and computer printout (Box 9)
    - Landscape, handwritten (Oversize 36)
    - Lo how a rose, handwritten copies (Box 9)
    - Lord you give the great commission, 1987; 1 pg handwritten copy (Box 9)
    - A Love chronology, vellums; copies; full text, typed (poems by Henry Warren Potter); 2 folders (Oversize 36)
    - Love's philosophy, aka "Wedding song", poetry by Shelley; handwritten copies (Oversize 36)
    - Ma-oz tsur, typed/handwritten copy, computer printout (Box 9)
    - Mark Twain madrigals, handwritten copies; text, copied from various books; 2 folders (Box 9)
    - Musical afterthoughts, computer printout, handwritten sketch, text (Oversize 37)
    - Night and day, piano vocal score, copies (Box 9)
    - Not heat flames up and consumes, handwritten with corrections; possibly related to Whitman (Oversize 37)
    - O Lord give thy benediction, handwritten copy (Box 9)
    - O maggio Monteverdi, full score and viola part, mix of handwritten and copies (Oversize 37)
    - O many named beloved, "for Susan from Robert, a 10th anniversary gift"; handwritten copy (Box 9)
    - Oh what a beautiful city, handwritten final, handwritten draft, copies (Oversize 37)
    - The old man, computer printout (Box 9)
    - One more day, voice and strings, full score, handwritten (Oversize 37)
    - Parade, full score, copied and bound (Box 9)
    - Parade, handwritten parts (Oversize 37)
    - Peace, unfinished, copied (Box 9)
    - Philippine songs, manuscript copy, missing page 1 (Box 9)
    - Philosophies, "texts selected by George Elder and commissioned by his wife Joann Englehardt for his 50th birthday year"; vellums and copies; 2 folders (Box 9)
    - Poems Penyeach, vellums and vellum copies; 2 folders (Oversize 37)
    - Prayer from Hansel and Gretel, alt. title "Evening prayer"; vocal score copy, parts handwritten (Box 9)
    - Preludes, miscellaneous, 12 preludes, 3 of them incomplete, plus sketches; handwritten, in original order (Oversize 37)
    - Psalm 23, vocal-organ score, computer printout copies (Box 9)
    - Psalm 39, vocal-organ score, computer printout copies (Box 9)
    - Psalm 84, alternate title "Max's Psalm"; multiple revisions, mix of handwritten and computer printout, taken as-is from original binder (Oversize 37)
    - Psalm 84, alternate title "Max's Psalm"; text, notes, revisions, etc. (Oversize 37)
    - Psalm 117, handwritten copy (Box 9)
    - Psalm 150, "unfinished"; computer printout copy (Box 9)
    - Punch and Judy Piano Suite, full score, handwritten copy; Waltz of Punch and Pretty Poll, handwritten (Oversize 37)
    - Quittez pasteurs, handwritten copies (Box 9)
    - Realization, handwritten copy (Box 9)
    - Rorate, handwritten copy (Box 9)
    - Sakura, vocal and bell choir part (Oversize 37)
    - Say it with music, "dedicated t0 50th anniversary of Warren and Lois Adee"; handwritten copy, computer printout (Box 9)
    - Serenade for flute, two clarinets, and strings, full score, copy (Oversize 37)
    - Seven last words, director's full score and libretto, vellum copies, bound (Oversize 38)
    - Seventeen come Sunday, copy, marked (Box 9)
    - Shalom, computer printout (Box 9)
    - Sierdtse, in Russian; computer printout (Box 9)
    - Sirens, handwritten copy, bound (Box 9)
    - Smoke, "small poem for voice and string trio", words by Thoreau; handwritten, 1 pg vellum (Oversize 38)
    - Solfeggio, piano score, handwritten (Oversize 38)